(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-21T22:35:44.461782",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Ooh!
Yeah, let's go!
Huh?
What the bip?!
Ah, ah, ah, ah!
Dang it!
Aw, man...
What's going on?
Where... where am I?
Huh? No way! Did I get sucked into the game world?!
Oh, what... what do I do?
Hello?
Uh... why are there so many eyes on me?
He- Hello?
Hello?
They're not saying anything.
Uh, I have to get back!
Today is such an important day, I can't get stuck in here!
Uh, what should I do?
I guess I have to figure this out on my own. Um...
Well...
There's so many people looking at me. Are those Pebbles? Hello!
Are you expecting me to do something?
Maybe I should... sing and dance? 'Cause this looks like a stage. Maybe...
Lemme see how I get out. Okay.
Let me see how I get out. Okay.
Okay, I got it then. I'm gonna sing and dance a song right now!
Here we go!
This game!
This game
回り続ける歯車には成り下がらない
I won't lower myself to become an endlessly spinning cog
平均演じる 誕生から始まった地獄
A hell that started from birth, acting like an average person
遊び半分で 神が導いた 盤上の世界
A world on a board guided by God for fun
no no no game no life
ぬるい平穏を ばっさり切り捨てて
Cutting away the lukewarm peace
栄光への階段に 存在刻むんだ
I will engrave my existence on the stairway to glory
目に映るのは 完全勝利の運命
What is reflected in my eyes is a destiny of absolute victory
何もかも 計算どおり
Everything is according to calculation
変えてやる 染まらない空白で
I'll change it with an untainted blank
We are maverick 救済なんていらない
We are maverick, we don't need salvation
どんな理不尽 襲おうとも
No matter what unfairness attacks us
勝てばいいだけの話だろう
It's just a matter of winning, right?
駆け引きと 才能が 無敗誘う
Bargaining and talent invite invincibility
生まれ直した命で 楽しむさ
We'll enjoy it with our reborn lives
自分だけは 自分信じてる
Only believing in ourselves
心に潜む闇より 強い相手はいない
There is no opponent stronger than the darkness lurking in the heart
挫けぬ限り そこに敗北は あり得ない
As long as you don't yield, defeat is impossible there
上べの個性で 安心と引き換えに プライド殺すな
Don't kill your pride in exchange for peace with superficial individuality
no no no sense of life
野蛮な雑音を きっぱり蹴飛ばして
Completely kicking away barbaric noise
誰より純粋な 声上げるんだ
I'll raise a voice purer than anyone else
戦うことは きっと間違いじゃない
Fighting is surely not a mistake
手応えが教えてくれた
The response taught me so
全て失っても 勝ち残れ
Even if you lose everything, survive and win
We are maverick 常識なんていらない
We are maverick, we don't need common sense
前へならえ 向かう先に
Following the line, what waits ahead
待ってるのは退屈だろう
Is probably boredom
言いなりじゃ つまらない 挑んでやる
Just obeying is boring, I'll challenge it
生まれ直した命も 駒にして
Making even our reborn lives into pawns
自分だけの道を 最後まで
Walking our own path until the very end
迷わない 選ばれし者
Unwavering, chosen ones
真っ赤なうぬぼれでも
Even if it's pure arrogance
誇らしく生き抜くための方法を
A way to survive proudly
一つしか知らないから
Because I only know one way
迷わない 選ばれし者の
Unwavering, chosen ones'
真っ赤なうぬぼれでも
Even if it's pure arrogance
誇らしく生き抜くための
A way to survive proudly
方法を一つしか知らないから
Because I only know one way
We are maverick 救済なんていらない
We are maverick, we don't need salvation
どんな理不尽 襲おうとも
No matter what unfairness attacks us
勝てばいいだけの話だろう
It's just a matter of winning, right?
駆け引きと 才能が 無敗誘う
Bargaining and talent invite invincibility
生まれ直した命で 楽しむさ
We'll enjoy it with our reborn lives
この世界 手にして 笑うんだ
Taking this world in our hands, we'll laugh
We are maverick 最強の maverick gamers
We are maverick, the strongest maverick gamers
空白ならば 何者にもなれる
If we are blank, we can become anything
自分だけは 自分信じてる
Only believing in ourselves
We are maverick 最高の maverick gamers
We are maverick, the ultimate maverick gamers
空白ならば 何者にもなれる
If we are blank, we can become anything
自分だけは 自分信じてる
Only believing in ourselves
Yeah! How was that? That was the best performance ever, right?
Hey, over there! You liked it, right? Hey!
With this, I should be able to get back to my own world.
All right, everybody, pay me up, pebbles!
Ah! Why is it changing? No!
No! My coins! Where are you going?
Dang it. Well, according to video game logic, this must mean I must now go on an epic quest to find the coins or something.
But I don't have time for that! I need the coins back to get home! No!
Huh? Huh? Oh, what's this?
Uh, I mean, I came out through there, so maybe this will take me, you know, on my next step of my quest?
Well, better than being stuck here, so...
Let's go!
Huh? Huh? I'm not back in my world?
え？ここどこ？
Eh? Where am I?
待ってたよ、ビブー
I've been waiting for you, Biboo.
え？え？え？ロボ子先輩？
Eh? Eh? Eh? Roboco-senpai?
探しているのは…これ？
Is this... what you're looking for?
あ！コイン！コイン！
Ah! Coin! The coin!
これがないと元の世界に戻れないんでしょう？
Without this, you can't return to your original world, right?
でも、そうはさせない。ゲームマスターである僕たちからすべて取り戻せるかな？
But I won't let you. Can you reclaim them all from us, the Game Masters?
え？本当？帰れるの？
Eh? Really? I can go back?
とにかく、このコインが欲しければ僕と勝負だ！
Anyway, if you want this coin, fight me!
What?
そう！格闘ゲームで勝負だ！
That's right! A battle in a fighting game!
All right! I won't lose!
リモコン
Remote Control
これが私をリモートコントロールする機械です
This is the machine that remotely controls me
少し歪な形しておりますが使えます
It's a bit of an awkward shape, but it works
もうちょっとで外に出られるのにな
Even though I'm so close to being able to go outside
どうやっても上手くいかねぇ
Nothing seems to work out
まだ まだ 足りない
Still, still, it's not enough!
座る 座る (oh) sit down please
Sitting down, sitting down, (oh) sit down please
フィードバックに体預けて
Surrendering my body to the feedback
廻る 廻る (oh) turn it around
Spinning, spinning, (oh) turn it around
うなりを上げて モーター状態
Revving up, like a motor
踊る 踊る (oh) dancin' night
Dancing, dancing, (oh) dancin' night
マッシュアップで漏れなくアガる
Getting hyped up with the mashup without fail
声を あげて (oh) singin' now
Raising our voices, (oh) singin' now
あの子よりも上手く歌いたい
I want to sing better than her
Ah, yeah!
これがボクをリモートで操縦できる機械です
This is the machine that can remotely control me
説明書は紛失しておりますが使えます
The instructions are missing, but it works
からかわれてるみたいないつもの顔
That usual face of yours that looks like you're teasing me
今日はかなり本気だぜ
Today I'm super serious
ほらすぐキメるぜ
Look, I'm gonna nail it right now!
座る 座る sit down please
Sit down, sit down, sit down please
トークバックを頭に挿して
Plugging the talkback into my head
まわる まわる turn it around
Spin around, spin around, turn it around
ちょっと待ってスタンバイ状態
Wait a sec, I'm on standby
踊る 踊る dancin' night
Dance, dance, dancin' night
ジャストフィットなリズムを出して
Laying down a perfectly fitting rhythm
うなりあげる singin' now
Howling out loud, singin' now
アイツよりも高く歌いたい
I wanna sing higher than her
惚れた晴れたの七色サムライ
Fallen in love, cleared up, the rainbow Samurai
洗いざらい主張する存在
A presence asserting everything inside out
思い違いが透けてる塩梅
A state where misunderstandings show right through
怖いくらいの wktk 状態
An almost scary state of excitement
気にしないのがアナタのポリシー？
Is not caring your policy?
悩んでいてもお腹は減るし
Even if you worry, you still get hungry
なんだかんだで世間はヘルシー
One way or another, society is healthy
お気を確かに ぬるま湯男子ぃ！
Get a grip, lukewarm guy!
もうちょっとでスキマ埋まるのに な
We're so close to filling in the gap...
どうやってもうまくいかね
No matter what, it doesn't go right
ああ もう時間が足りない！
Ah, there's just not enough time!
座る 座る sit down please
Sit down, sit down, sit down please
フィードバックに体預けて
Surrendering your body to the feedback
めぐる めぐる turn it around
Spin around, spin around, turn it around
うなりをあげてモーター状態
Revving up into motor mode
踊る 踊る dancin' night
Dance, dance, dancin' night
マッシュアップでもれなくアガる
Getting hyped up without exception in this mashup
声をあげて singin' now
Raise your voice, singin' now
あの子みたいなヒトになりたい
I want to become someone like her
座る 座る sit down please
Sit down, sit down, sit down please
めぐる めぐる turn it around
Spin around, spin around, turn it around
踊る 踊る dancin' night
Dance, dance, dancin' night
声をあげて singin' now
Raise your voice, singin' now
あの子みたいなヒトになりたい
I want to become someone like her
I win!
くやし〜
Frustrating~
Ah! Coin! Yay!
I got a coin. Huh?
Go to the next stage.
But 次のゲームマスターは僕のようにはいかないぞ
But the next game master won't be as easy as me!
No easy.
え〜 大丈夫だよ、ビブーだから！
Eh~ It's fine, because I'm Biboo!
Ah, okay.
うん！ありがとう先輩！
Mm! Thank you, Senpai!
じゃあ！バイバーイ！
Well then! Bye-bye!
Bye-bye! Congratulations!
Ooh, there...
Now then... Where to next, I wonder?
We've been waiting for you, Biboo!
Woah!
Huh? IRyS? Ina?
I'm assuming THIS is what you're looking for, right?
Yes! Yes, I need that! I need that! Yes, give it, give it, I need that coin!
We won't just hand it over.
You'll have to race us for it.
Huh?
Yes.
No, give it! Give it! Where are you putting that?
I'm putting that back in my pocket.
Nope! If you want it, you have to beat us.
Are you ready to battle?
Fine, I'll beat both of you for this.
Oh hey... I won't lose!
No one can dull my shine tonight
No one can dull my shine
Save me, I think I'm freezing up, so cold inside
舞台は Quiet room ふたり
The stage is a quiet room, just the two of us
Save me, I need a guiding touch in these dark times
恋人たちのシーン
A scene for lovers
Inside the maze of your heart, I'm the soul that strays (That's right)
But baby look at me, you're not blind. Oh, can't you see that I can be refined
Your heart is super hot right now
It's time to be your Diamond Girlfriend
Overheating love machine, burning hot! (Hot!) Hot! (Hot!) Hot! (Untouchable)
Silver flames consuming me, let them light the way (So precious girlfriend, go-go-go)
Overheating love machine, burning hot! (Hot!) Hot! (Hot!) Hot! (On the rock machine)
Nothing stops this awakened soul. Break it all, break it all, break it all
The Diamond Girlfriend しとやかキャラ豹変 ビート纏い
The Diamond Girlfriend, a sudden shift from a gentle persona, clad in the beat
まき散らすのは ブリンブリンの sparkle だ
Scattering around blings and sparkles
Just heat it and wheel it, make the sword バッチリ
Just heat it and wheel it, make the sword perfect
まぶしさで目が眩む gem
A gem whose dazzling light blinds your eyes
Trust me, your weary eyes betray what you've tried to hide
言葉無しで伝わり
Conveyed without words
Trust me, I'll never shy away from your dark side
空気が変わるフェイズ
A phase where the air changes
Under the pressure and fire, see these ashes reborn (Your rebirth)
Let me show you who I really am (Oh yeah)
In the name of love, I'll be a gem
Your heart is super hot right now
It's time I'll be your Diamond Girlfriend
Overheating love machine, burning hot! (Hot!) Hot! (Hot!) Hot! (Untouchable)
Silver flames consuming me, let them light the way (So precious girlfriend, go-go-go)
Overheating love machine, burning hot! (Hot!) Hot! (Hot!) Hot! (On the rock machine)
Nothing stops this awakened soul. Break it all, break it all, break it all
No one can dull my shine tonight
No one can dull my shine
Now "C" is your atomic symbol
ぐるぐる回せ 真っ赤っ赤になるまで wimble
Spin round and round until it turns bright red, wimble
愛が足りないとか 闇が深いほど
When love is lacking or the darkness is deep
価値ふえる gem 扱う I'm a jeweler
A gem whose value increases, I'm a jeweler handling it
さあ 踊リナサイ
Now, dance!
Shine on, shine bright, light my flame
Until it all melts away
Are you ready?
Overheating love machine, burning hot! (Hot!) Hot! (Hot!) Hot! (Untouchable)
Silver flames consuming me, let them light the way (So precious girlfriend, go-go-go)
Overheating love machine, burning hot! (Hot!) Hot! (Hot!) Hot! (On the rock machine)
Nothing stops this awakened soul. Break it all, break it all, break it all
No one can dull my shine tonight
No one can dull my shine
Yeah! Woohoo!
Are you guys okay?
No! / Yeah...
Did I hit you hard?
Dammit! I got the coin! I'm the winner! I win!
Huh? What's that? A portal?
Oh, a port-- By the way, where did the coin come from, IRyS?
Uh, um, it... / Don't worry about it!
It came from my Nephilim pocket!
Oh no! Goodbye!
Ah, the world is spinning!
I'm dizzy...
Huh? Is this a puzzle stage?
Hey! I'm ready for my next challenge now! Hey, come out! Hey!
Huh?
There's no Game Master this time?
Eh?
Well, I guess I could use a break or something then.
Mm, maybe I'll dance and sing by myself, you know, as a refresher.
Yeah, so I'll be ready for the next challenge!
Now this is a puzzle stage, so it does remind me of a certain song...
Hey, everyone over there! You wanna hear it too, right?
Yeah?
Okay. They didn't say anything, I'm just talking to myself.
Well, all right then! Let's dance... Tetris!
どうしてすぐ知ってしまうのだろう
Why do I end up finding out right away?
共振で苦しんで失望
Suffering and disappointed from resonance
更新で降る彗星 抹消可？ 悪くない
Comets falling with updates—can they be erased? Not bad
興味ねえ 救い 派手 感動
No interest in salvation, flashy emotion
常備ねえ 薬 食べ bad
No spare meds, taking them feels bad
超酷え フル 見た目 暗号化？
Super awful, fully encoded looks?
金による
Driven by money
常識ねえ 狂いっぱなしで乱闘
No common sense, going crazy in a brawl
放置ゲーする 陰キャでバンド
An introverted band playing idle games
送信で苦しい ダメ cancel は？ 草生える
Painful to send, can't cancel it? LOL
どうしてすぐ見てしまうの
Why do I end up looking right away?
どうしてすぐ言ってしまうの
Why do I end up saying it right away?
どうしてすぐ壊れちゃうかな
Why does it break so easily?
(パパラ パラパラ)
(Papara parapara)
近未来しか勝たん
The near future is the best
ショッピングモールの現代コンピュー
Modern compu- in shopping malls
小窓 戻る か 加担
Small window, returning or taking part
モンテカルロの経費でピンボール
Pinball funded by Monte Carlo expenses
オイルマッサージ 100分コース 足湯付き
100-minute oil massage course with foot bath
柚子を添えて
Garnished with yuzu
テテ テテトテト テテ テテ トリス
Te-te tetoteto te-te te-te -tris
どうしてこんな目に に に
Why did this happen to me, me, me?
興味がないこと 本気じゃないもの 全部後回しで
Putting off everything I'm not interested in or serious about,
知ってることは知らんぷり 私は終わってる
Pretending not to know what I know—I'm done for.
恥ずかしい過去知ってる奴らの記憶消させて
Let me erase the memories of those who know my embarrassing past,
迷惑かけてごめんってば ねえ誰か助けて
I said I'm sorry for causing trouble, someone help me.
妄信ですぐ惹かれちゃうの
Easily captivated by blind faith,
狂信ですぐ引かれちゃうの
Easily turned off by fanaticism.
知リたくない 知りたくない 知りたくない
Don't want to know, don't want to know, don't want to know.
(タタラ タラタラ)
(Tatara taratara)
もう見ねえ すぐ引かれ sad
Won't look anymore, drawn away immediately, sad
常勤で狂いたて mad
Full-time gone crazy, mad
行きたくない 行きたくない 生きたくない
Don't want to go, don't want to go, don't want to live
ばーいばい
Bye-bye
臨時休業 洗濯ボール
Temporary closure, laundry ball
ナイチンゲールの配信ゲーム
Nightingale's streamed game
名刺交換の名シーン
Famous scene of exchanging business cards
借金ボウルでチンチロ ハイボール
Chinchiro highball in a bowl of debt
温泉旅行 3泊4日 食事付き
3 nights, 4 days hot spring trip with meals included
早く行きてえ
I wanna go so bad
テテ テテトテト テテ テテ トリス
Te-te tetoteto te-te te-te -tris
共感性 羞 恥 恥
Empathic embarrass- -ment, -ment
鬱とか躁とか忙しくて眠れないわ今日も
Depressed or manic, so busy I can't sleep today either
誰か早く殴って気絶させてくれよ
Someone hurry and punch me unconscious
人生キャンセル キャンセル界隈
Life cancellation, cancellation circles
ぼんやりとした不安
Vague anxiety
私のせい 私が悪いよ そうだよ
It's my fault, I'm to blame, that's right
興味が出ても本気でやっても全部空回りで
Even if I get interested or take it seriously, it all goes in circles,
知らないくせに嘘つき 私は終わってる
A liar despite not knowing—I'm done for.
恥ずかしい過去知ってる奴らの記憶消させて
Let me erase the memories of those who know my embarrassing past,
迷惑かけてごめんってば ねえ誰か助けて
I said I'm sorry for causing trouble, someone help me,
迷惑かけてごめんってば ねえ誰か許して
I said I'm sorry for causing trouble, someone forgive me.
Ow... dizzy...
Whoa, that scared me!
I don't know, this game's bugged, man! Hey, someone report these bugs!
Dang it! Cubes are popping out and everything is...
...designed like this? I need to meet the devs! Hey, devs!
This game is malfunctioning, but I don't have time for that! I gotta find the coins!
Eh? Ah, I guess that's my cue to leave.
Okay! Next stage, let's charge up! Helicopter! Helicopter!
Whoa!
I gotta work on that landing.
Eh? Oh, wow, what a cute stage! Cute!
Ho ho ho ho ho!
どうもどうも待ってましたよ、ビブー！
Hello hello, I've been waiting for you, Biboo!
白上フブキ 参戦！
[Shirakami Fubuki Joins the Battle!]
Fubuki-san! Why?!
ビブーはこれが欲しいんだよね？
Biboo, you want this, don't you?
I want! I want!
ならば白上と勝負だ！白上のクレーンゲームから落として逃げられるかな？
Then it's a battle against Shirakami! Can you drop it from my crane game and escape?
Ummm, okay then! I won't lose!
LONELY ROLLING STAR
日だまり
Sunspot,
サンサン
shining brightly.
ココロは
My heart is
ハレ模様
bright and sunny.
ふたつの
These two
瞳は
eyes are
ヒマワリ
like sunflower
の種のように
seeds.
語らい
Chatting,
重なり
overlapping,
塊
a clump,
絡まり
entangled.
一緒に
Being together
居ること
is an
絶対
absolute
必然
necessity.
でもアナタ大事な
But as you draw
夢を描く
your precious dream,
終わるまではずっと
until it's over,
此処で待っている
I'll be right here waiting for you.
You're lonely rolling star
立ち止まらないでね
Don't stop moving, okay?
You're lonely rolling star
さぁ前を向いて行こう
So face forward and keep going!
星空
Starry sky,
キラキラ
glittering
金平糖のよう
like konpeito candy.
甘くて
Sweet
切ない
and bittersweet,
想いが募るの
my feelings grow stronger.
抱きしめた想いは
The feelings I hold tight
夜空を舞い
dance across the night sky,
急降下して
swooping down
あなたの下へ届くから
to reach down by your side.
You're lonely rolling star
諦めないでよね
Don't give up, okay?
You're lonely rolling star
たまには電話して
Call me once in a while.
You're lonely rolling star
会いたいよ今スグ
I want to see you right now!
You're lonely rolling star
ため息が
Ah, a single sigh
ひとつこぼれる
spills over.
来月またあの場所で
Next month, shall we meet up again
待ち合わせしようか
at that same place?
You're lonely rolling star
立ち止まらないでね
Don't stop moving, okay?
You're lonely rolling star
思い出してよねぇ
Remember me, won't you?
You're lonely rolling star
待ってられないのねぇ
I can't keep on waiting!
You're lonely rolling star
さぁ前を向いて行こう
So face forward and keep going!
Yaaay! I won! I won!
あれ？ 使われちゃった…
Huh? I got used...
あひー！ ボコボコにされたよー！
Ahee! I got totally beaten up!
Coin, yeah! You're the coin! Yeah!
I'm the winner! 可愛い可愛いして、しょうがない、許す！
I'm the winner! Pamper me 'cause I'm cute, I can't help it, forgive me!
可愛いからね！ じゃあ次の世界へ、ビブー！
Because you're cute! Well then, to the next world, Biboo!
あ、フブキングがー！
Ah, Fubuking is...!
助けて！ 先輩、お願い！
Save me! Senpai, please!
はい、行くぞー！
Alright, let's go!
Let's go, Fubuki!
Ah, there!
I think we're doing great now, aren't we?
Who's next? Huh, I'm ready for my next challenger!
待っていたぞ、ビブー！
I've been waiting for you, Biboo!
轟はじめ 参戦！ リズムダンスバトル
[Todoroki Hajime Joins the Battle! Rhythm Dance Battle]
Hajime?! What?!
これが欲しければ、拙者と勝負だ！
If you want this, face me in a duel!
My coin!
ハジメのダンスについてこれるかな？
Can you keep up with Hajime's dance?
Eh? Dance? Hm... Aah...
Okay! Let's dance together!
ヤー！ ヤー！
Ya! Ya!
「みんなー！チルののさんすう教室はじまるよー！」
Everyone! Cirno's math class is starting!
「あたいみたいな天才目指して、がんばっていってね！」
Aim to be a genius like me, and do your best!
キラキラ ダイヤモンド 輝く星のように
Sparkling diamond, like a shining star,
栄光 志望校 なんとかして入ろう
Glory! First-choice school! Let's get in somehow!
天才 秀才 トップ目指して GO GO!!
Genius, prodigy! Aim for the top, GO GO!!
(バーカバーカ バーカバーカ バーカバーカ)
(Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!)
「ちょっ、ちがっ、バカじゃないもん！」
"Wha- No! I'm not an idiot!"
(バーカバーカ バーカバーカ バーカバーカ)
(Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!)
「バカっていうほうがバカなのよ！」
"Whoever calls others idiots is the real idiot!"
(バーカバーカ バーカバーカ バーカバーカ)
(Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!)
「何よ、うるさいわね！このバカ！」
"What?! Shut up, you idiot!"
(バーカバーカ バーカバーカ)
(Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!)
てれんてれん てれんてれん てっ てっ てっ てっ てれん
Teren-terenteren-teren te-te-te-te-teren
紅魔館からバスが出て 始めに三人乗りました
A bus left the Scarlet Devil Mansion with three passengers at first,
白玉楼で一人降りて 半人だけ乗りました
One got off at Hakugyokurou, and half a person got on,
八雲さんちで二人降りて 結局乗客合計何人だ？
Two got off at the Yakumos' house, so how many passengers are there in total?
答えは 答えは 0人 0人
The answer, the answer is zero people, zero people!
なぜなら なぜなら それは
That's because, that's because, it's because...
幻想郷にバスは無い
There are no buses in Gensokyo!
山 落ち 意味など無いわ
Climax, resolution, meaning—there's none of that!
キャラクター立てばいいのよ
As long as the characters stand out, it's fine!
元気があればなんでも
As long as you have energy, anything goes!
1・2・九!!
1, 2, 9!!
くるくる 時計の針
Round and round go the clock hands,
ぐるぐる 頭まわる
Round and round goes my head spinning,
だって つぶら目玉 二つしかないのに
After all, I only have two round eyes,
三本の針なんて ちんぷんかん
So three clock hands make no sense at all!
次々 問題出る
Problem after problem comes up,
まだまだ 授業続く
Class is still going on and on,
凍る 部屋の中 ひんやりした温度も
Inside the freezing room, without caring about the cool temperature or time,
時間も気にせず ゆっくりしていってね！
Take it easy!
(バーカバーカ バーカバーカ バーカバーカ)
(Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!)
「だからバカじゃないって言ってるでしょ！」
"I keep telling you I'm not an idiot!"
(バーカバーカ バーカバーカ バーカバーカ)
(Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!)
「いいかげんにしないとお仕置きするわよ！」
"Cut it out or I'm gonna punish you!"
(バーカバーカ バーカバーカ バーカバーカ)
(Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!)
「そして粉々になって死ねばいいのよ！」
"And then you can get smashed to pieces and die!"
(バーカバーカ バーカバーカ)
(Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!)
てれんてれん てれんてれん てっ てっ てっ てっ てれん
Teren-terenteren-teren te-te-te-te-teren
霊夢んところの 百万円の 壺を誰かが割っちゃった
Someone broke Reimu's one-million-yen vase,
永遠亭の えーりんが 弁償に来ましたよ
Eirin from Eientei came to offer compensation!
知らんぷりの イタズラでね 結局賠償金額いくら？
Feigning ignorance about the prank, how much is the final compensation amount?
答えは 答えは なぜなら なぜなら それは
The answer, the answer, because, because...
そんな壺あるわけない
There's no way such a vase exists!
常識 超えたところに
Beyond common sense,
世界の真理がある
Lies the truth of the world,
秘密の数字目指して
Aiming for the secret numbers,
1・2・九!!
1, 2, 9!!
ヘラヘラ ニヤニヤしながら ゲラゲラ 笑いながら
Snicker, smirk, laugh out loud!
うっぜー！
So annoying!
因幡ウサギ
Inaba rabbit,
可愛げもないのに
with no charm at all,
新参の厨どもは ハイハイハイ
you new geeks are all "Yeah, yeah, yeah."
再生百万回
A million views,
もれなく愚民なんて
and every single one of you is a fool,
どういうことなのよ
what is the meaning of this?
どちらかって言うなら さあ
If I had to say, well,
管理もお疲れさんってとこね
thanks for managing all of this.
「わかった！」
"I got it!"
「アタイがあまりにも天才だから嫉妬してるんでしょ」
"You're just jealous because I'm such a genius, right?"
「ほんと、しょうがないわね」
"Honestly, you're hopeless."
「せっかくだからアタイの天才の秘法を」
"Since we're here, I'll teach you..."
「ちょっとだけ教えてあげてもいいわよ」
"...a little bit of my secret genius ways!"
あーゆるゆーゆるゆーゆるゆー 智哲を
Gathering all kinds of wisdom and intelligence...
集めて集めて集めて集めて 束ねても
Gathering, gathering, gathering, bundling them up,
アタイの アタイの アタイのアタイのアタイのアタイの
my, my, my, my, my, my...
丈夫な頭に集まれ集まれ集まれ集まれ かなわい
...sturdy head gathers them, but it can't beat me!
食べたら 食べたら 食べたら 食べたら 食べたら 食べたら 食べたら
If you eat, eat, eat, eat, eat, eat, eat it,
赤子の赤子の赤子の赤子の 手をひねる
it's like twisting a baby's hand!
アタイは アタイは アタイのアタイのアタイのアタイの カンペキ
I am, I am, my, my, my, my perfect...
いわゆるいわゆるいわゆるいわゆる パーフェクト
...so-called, so-called, so-called perfection!
ひゃ〜おくちょうまん バッチリ！
100-billion-trillion percent perfect!
山落ち 意味など無いわ
Climax or meaning? There's no such thing.
キャラクター 立てばいいのよ
As long as the character stands out, it's fine!
元気があればなんでも
If you have energy, you can do anything!
① ② ⑨！
One, two, nine!
くるくる 時計の針
Spinning around, the clock hands turn.
くるくる 頭まわる
Spinning around, my head is spinning.
だって つぶら目玉 二つしかないのに
After all, even though I only have two round eyes,
三本の針なんて ちんぷんかんぷん
three clock hands are total gibberish to me!
次々 問題出る
Questions pop up one after another,
まだまだ 授業続く
and class just keeps on going.
凍る 部屋の中 ひやりした温度も 時間も
Inside the freezing room, the chilly temperature and time,
気にせず ゆっくりしていかない？
without a care, won't you take it easy?
バーカ バーカ
Idiot, idiot,
idiot, idiot,
バーカ バーカ
バーカ！ バーカ！
Idiot! Idiot!
バーカ バーカ...
Idiot, idiot...
「もうバカでいいわよ！知らん！」
"Fine, call me an idiot! I don't care!"
てれん てれん てれん てれん...
Teren teren teren teren...
Whew! High-energy dance, continuous mode... not bad at all.
Yeah! Coin acquired!
Hah! Yay! I got a coin!
Nerissa! Thank you for dancing with me! That was so much fun!
It was fun! Thank you!
So, I must go. Woah, okay!
Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
Whew!
Oh, always ready, okay. Ah, I see.
Woah! What's next then? The rest is... let's count.
1, 2... 2 challenges left, I think, for 2 coins.
バトルスタート！
Battle Start!
天音かなた・ラプラス・ダークネス 参戦！
[Amane Kanata & La+ Darknesss Join the Battle!]
Eh? Kanata-senpai? La+? What are you doing here?
これが欲しければ... 我々と勝負だ！
If you want this... fight us!
My coin!
迫り来るゾンビを 全員 倒すことが... 出来るかなー！？
Can you defeat all the approaching zombies... I wonder?!
Well... じゃあ、手加減はしない！
Well... then I won't hold back!
Run away, run away, run away, you don't know who to run from
Nowhere to go, nowhere to go, nowhere to go, no road is left to run on
I was born, I was born with horns, demons couldn't shake me up
Bring it on, bring it on, bring it on
'Cause we haven't had enough
Won't give up the fight
Make it out alive
Set this world on fire now, woah, woah
Don't give up, it's gonna be alright
'Cause I won't let you burn out, woah, woah
We gotta make it out alive
Tonight, tonight, tonight
I'm screamin' on the inside
I was tryin' to hide, tryin' to hide, tryin' to hide
Not ready for this ride
Gotta face, gotta face the unknown
It's the only way to live
I'm ready to go, ready to go, ready to go somewhere I've never been
Make it out alive
Set this world on fire now
Woah, woah
Don't give up, it's gonna be alright
'Cause I won't let you burn out
Woah, woah
We gotta make it out alive
Make it out alive
Set this world on fire now
Woah, woah
Don't give up, it's gonna be alright
'Cause I won't let you burn out
Woah, woah
We gotta make it out alive
Yeah, yeah
Yeah, make it out, make it out
We gotta make it out alive
全部倒すなんて すっげーじゃん！
Defeating all of them is awesome!
あ、終わった？
Ah, is it over?
それー！よし！
That's right! Alright!
コインをやろう！
Let me give you a coin!
あ！コイン！イエース！
Ah! A coin! Yaaay!
じゃ、みんなありがとね。
Well, thank you everyone.
ハッピーバースデー！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
オッケー！
Okay!
じゃ、さようならー！
Well, goodbye!
くっそ！なんで動けない...
Damn it! Why can't I move...
Nice landing! Yeah!
Huh?
Oh, it's the first stage.
Maybe this is like a progress check sort of thing?
Let's see where I'm at, huh?
Ooh, I'm missing one more coin,
but where could it be?
Is anyone here to give me another game or something?
Woah! Woah!
Maybe this is like the safe zone where I can like take a break and recover?
That's a good idea! You know,
I'm feeling kind of tired, and all the songs have been so banger, intense...
Let's take a break.
It's just a nap. I'll wake up...
Hold on, everyone. Just give me like 5 minutes, okay? Just 5 minutes.
おやすみ a little.
Good night for a little bit.
You know, おやすみ. See ya, see ya.
You know, good night. See ya, see ya.
Well come and well met, my brave little spark
How long you've wandered, burned bright as a star
Oh, I have awaited you patiently all this time
Past every fate
Now sing with me once more, share of your life
Far greater than memory,
its loss and love words cannot hold
Boundless the tale overflows
And carries your light out to sea
Remember the rain, near and far beloved
Each drop a blessing from heavens above
And how as time flowed on those waters became one
Streams, rivers and lakes
Reaching for the horizon and far beyond
They carry onward however changed
with each brief reflection, by setting sun
By storm's wake
Til welcomed home to gentle sea
Sinking deeper and deeper in calm embrace
Loving tides sweep in and bear you down
Should you meet a soul rising surface-ways
With your unbeating heart, wish them well
Deep, dark, far away,
I have heard your voice, weighed your every choice
Now our hands join round the meaning you sought
I'll catch your tears, quench your fears
with joy til you near the shore
Where in time, all shall as hope be reborn, ah
Hush, love, close your eyes, and in sleep abide
As sun's distant light, echoes down to dreams below
Know you will wake, on winds rise again
For this journey's end
is but one step forward to tomorrow
What a good dream!
Alright, let's check our progress then.
Hmm, we're still missing one coin. Where could it be?
Ah! Ah, again?!
What's happening?!
Wah! Ah!
What the biboo?!
I've been waiting for you, Bijou.
Fake Biboo Joins the Battle!
You... You're...
I'm you.
Me? You mean, my last opponent is me?
Exactly.
Me...
You.
Your biggest enemy. Your biggest obstacle. Yourself.
No...
You've done well at making it this far, Bijou.
But I don't intend to hold back.
Then I won't either! This day is too important for me to give up now!
Weight of the World / 壊レタ世界ノ歌
[Song: Weight of the World / Song of the Broken World]
I feel like I'm losing hope
In my body and my soul
And the sky, it looks so ominous
And as time comes to a halt
Silence starts to overflow
My cries are inconspicuous
Tell me God, are you punishing me?
Is this the price I'm paying for my past mistakes?
This is my redemption song
I need you more than ever right now
Can you hear me now?
Cause we're gonna shout it loud
Even if our words seem meaningless
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
I wish that someway, somehow
That I could save every one of us
But the truth is that I'm only one girl
Maybe if I keep believing
My dreams will come to life
Come to life
溢れる緑
Overflowing greenery,
零れる命
spilling life.
風は今も遠く
The wind is still far away even now.
剥がれる錆と 蠢く刃
Peeling rust and a writhing blade.
死が潜む森に
In the forest where death lurks.
これが僕の呪い
This is my curse.
約束殺す痛みが
The pain that kills promises...
キミの願い
...is your wish.
最後の夢を捨てた
I discarded my final dream.
償いだけど
Though it's an atonement,
そう僕らは今
yes, right now, we...
ああ 無価値でも叫ぶ
Ah, even if it's worthless, we shout
この汚れた世界の愛
love for this corrupted world.
そう僕らは今
Yes, right now, we...
ああ 無意味でも願う
Ah, even if it's meaningless, we pray
ただキミとの時間を
simply for time with you.
溺れた意識は 優しいまま消えて
Drowning consciousness fades away while remaining gentle...
'Cause we're gonna shout it loud
Even if our words seem meaningless
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
そう 僕らは今
Yes, we are now...
ああ 無意味でも願う
Ah, even if it's meaningless, I pray...
ただ君との未来を
...just for a future with you.
Still, we're gonna shout it loud
Even if our words seem meaningless
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
I hope that someway, somehow / そう 僕らは今
I hope that someway, somehow... / Yes, we are now...
That I could save every one of us / ああ 無意味でも願う
...that I could save every one of us... / Ah, even if it's meaningless, I pray...
ただ君との時間を
...just for time with you.
Maybe if I keep believing / 祈りが赦しを得られずとも
Maybe if I keep believing... / Even if my prayer grants no forgiveness...
My dreams will come to life
僕は...
I am...
Impressive.
Yes! The coin!
Oh, you're still alive. Oh.
You who have defeated all the game masters shall be rewarded.
Huh? What is this?
Now, show this to everyone.
Yeah! Hey, thanks! But um...
There can only be one!
Oh, I'm here! Oh!
Hello, everyone! We have made it to the final stage!
You didn't think I collected all those coins and played all those games for nothing, did you?
No, because I'm cashing in! With all of these coins, we have unlocked...
...my new original song!
And guess what? The video's gonna come out right after this! Good job, everyone!
And I'm gonna perform it to you right now! Are you ready? Let's go out with a bang! ROCK IN!
Biboo's here to play
Yeah, uh-huh
Woke up in the morning
I had a funny dream
I was a stone that had been thrown
No way back, I was all in
What if that was me soaring straight to the top?
Let's take a chance, game on, and shoot my shot
Log in, get good, you mad? Let's cook
Talk beep, get hit, clean sweep
Now you know what's up, hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo Biboo
Come and test your luck, yeah we comin' in clutch, Biboo Biboo
Skipping stone in flight, take 'em out one-shot, Biboo Biboo
Come and help me fight, get on up, let's go, just me and you
Player one and player two
We'll see this through
Close my eyes, make a wish
One more shot, I will not miss
ROCK IN!
Bububa bububu ba...
Level up, we go onwards
Aiming for another win
A diamond in the rough, it's kinda tough, you gotta keep on rollin'
The grind goes on and on, no breaks
Seal the cracks with a few bandaids
I'll try over and over and over again
Just one more round, please?
Now you know what's up
Hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo Biboo
Come and test your luck
Yeah we comin' in clutch, Biboo Biboo
Yeah, we're comin' in clutch, Biboo Biboo
Skipping stone in flight
Take 'em out one-shot, Biboo Biboo
Come and help me fight
Get on up, let's go, just me and you
Player one and player two
We'll see this through
Close my eyes, make a wish
One more shot, I will not miss
ROCK IN!
Lost in this game, I feel the strain
But I'm pulled back up by your gravity
Your gravity
I see the shape, I feel the space
It's set in stone, carve it into me
I just wanna be Biboo
Now you know what's up
Hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo Biboo
Come and test your luck
Yeah we comin' in clutch, Biboo Biboo
Yeah, we're comin' in clutch, Biboo Biboo
Skipping stone in flight
Take 'em out one-shot, Biboo Biboo
Better hit quick save 'cause
Biboo's here to play
Now you know what's up
Hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo Biboo
Come and test your luck
Yeah we comin' in clutch, Biboo Biboo
Yeah, we're comin' in clutch, Biboo Biboo
Skipping stone in flight
Take 'em out one-shot, Biboo Biboo
Come and help me fight
Get on up, let's go, just me and you
Player one and player two
We'll see this through
Close my eyes, make a wish
One more shot, I will not miss
ROCK IN!
Biboo Biboo!
Uh...
Hello?
Um, I'm still here.
Uh, ready to get teleported back to my world any, any time now.
Mom?
Pick me up.
I'm scared.
Hey! This was not part of the deal!
Hey!
No, wait! What are you doing? No! No! No! No!
Hey, listen to my song at least!
Okay, my song's coming out, listen to it!
ROCK IN! Go! Go! Ahhh!
Biboo's here to play
Yeah, uh-huh, ah ah
Let's go!
Woke up in the morning
I had a funny dream
I was a stone that had been thrown
No way back, I was all in (I was all in)
What if that was me soaring straight to the top?
Let's take a chance, game on and shoot my shot
Log in, get good, you mad? Let's cook
Talk beep, get hit, clean sweep, let's go
Now you know what's up
Hit 'em with a 1-2-3, Biboo Biboo